## Iehedi Hasan

**J** (+880)196-950-0278

mhasan912@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/moidda

https://github.com/Moidda

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

I am a **Software Engineer** specializing in Research at Chaldal. Outside of work, I am involved in academic research. My primary area of interest is Human Computer Interaction. I'm also passionate about Visualization, VR/AR, and Ubiquitous technologies. Through my work experience, I've gained expertise and interest in **Algorithms** and **Systems**, including Networking, Distributed Systems and System Design.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BSc in Computer Science and Engineering**

May 2023

Total: 112

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET), Dhaka, Bangladesh

**Notable Courses:** 

CSE 305 - Computer Architecture CSE 309 - Compiler

CSE 321 - Computer Networks CSE 463 - Introduction to Bioinformatics

CSE 409 - Computer Graphics CSE 471 - Machine Learning CSE 461 - Algorithm Engineering MATH 247 - Linear Algebra

MATH 145 - Calculus and Coordinate Geometry CSE 313 - Operating System CSE 405 - Computer Security HUM 477 - Sociology for Science and Technology

#### ENGLISH PROFICIENCY

TOEFL iBT December, 2023

Reading: 25, Listening: 28, Speaking: 30, Writing: 29

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Mubassira, T., Hasan, M., Sharmin, S. (2024). "Reading the Mind's Eye: Detecting Trauma-Vulnerability in Individuals by Analyzing Attention Through Eye-Tracking". In: Zaslavsky, A., Ning, Z., Kalogeraki, V., Georgakopoulos, D., Chrysanthis, P.K. (eds) Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services. MobiQuitous 2023 (EAI Mobiguitous 2023). DOI: 10.1007/978-3-031-63992-0\_28
- Mubassira, T., Hasan, M., Mukta, J., Islam, A (2024). "Enhancing EmoBot: An In-Depth Analysis of User Expectation and Satisfaction in An Emotion-Aware Chatbot". In: International Conference on Networking, Systems and Security, 2024. (Peer Reviewed)

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Towards perceiving and resolving the impediments to reporting for the developing countries

Human Computer Interaction, Generic Reporting System

Aug 2024 - Current

- DOI: 10.1109/NSYSS2.2017.8267790
- Live At: ureporter.cse.buet.ac.bd
- Supervisor: Dr. A. B. M. Alim Al Islam, Professor, CSE, BUET
- Collaboration: With Tarik Reza Toha, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill
- **Contribution:** Improved the system in collaboration with the research team

#### Detecting Sentiment in Anonymous Submissions: A Study on User Report Data

Human Computer Analysis, Sentiment Analysis

Sep 2024 - Current

- Supervisor: Dr. A. B. M. Alim Al Islam, Professor, CSE, BUET
- Contribution: Performed sentiment analysis on crowd sourced anonymous reports

#### Fine-Tuning GPT-2 for Bengali Auto Text Completion Using Literary Corpus: A Qualitative Analysis

Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning

Jan 2023 - Mar 2023

- Presentation: Slides
- Supervisor: Dr. Mohammed Eunus Ali, Professor, CSE, BUET
- Contribution: Fine-tuned GPT-2 with a Bengali literature corpus to improve auto text completion

Chaldal Ltd. June 2023 – Present

R&D

#### **ASAP Delivery**

- Designed an algorithm to calculate geographical area overlapping a route, through which a driver can detour for a specific slack time period without impacting other deliveries in the route
- Impact: Grocery delivery within 20 to 40 minutes in Dhaka

### Last Mile Routing Algorithm

- Designed a new routing algorithm using different heuristic and probabilistic search methods
- Impact: Increased on-time delivery by 15%

#### Traffic Estimate

- Developed a timeseries database and supervised an interpolation project using spatio-temporal models to fill missing traffic speed data.
- Impact: Improved estimates for Dhaka roads by 53.53% for cycles, 28.83% for motorbikes, and 28.73% for vans
   Automate Task Assignment
- Designed and deployed an algorithm for solving the task assignment problem via an API endpoint, integrated into a system for periodic task assignment within the warehouse.
- Impact: Increased on-time dispatch by 16%

#### System Design

#### Micro-services communication

- Designed and implemented a **gRPC-based communication system** across three services to transmit information at specific events, tested it in a QA environment, and oversaw its system-wide deployment.
- **Impact:** Decreased driver idle time by 7 minutes

### Spatial Database Model

- Developed a **spatial database model** which can store polygonal area and query with intersecting geolocation
- Impact: Enhanced vehicle utilization by restricting certain vehicle types in specific areas

#### Re-Modeling Task Assignment system

- Designed a more efficient task assignment model, refactored existing models, redesigned the UI, and improved underlying logic.
- Impact: Increased picker's efficiency by 1.2x

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- $-5^{th}/50$  teams Code Samurai Hackathon 2022
- 8<sup>th</sup>/86 teams BUET CSE FEST IUPC 2019
- 10<sup>th</sup>/84 teams DUET IUPC 2019
- 13<sup>th</sup>/59 teams National Programming Contest
- Hackerrank: Problem Solving (Intermediate)
- Codeforces Max Rating: Expert (1871)

#### **SELECTED PROJECTS**

#### Trapped (Game)

Unity Game Engine, C#

Developed a 2D action and puzzle platformer

#### P5js-Raycasting

Javascript, HTML

Implemented raycasting using p5-js library for visualization

#### xv6 Memory Management (OS)

Linux, C, bash, kernel programming

Enhanced the xv6 operating system by adding support for memory management.

#### Simple C Compiler

C, YACC, Bison

Developed a C compiler capable of reading small C programs and generating corresponding machine code for execution.

#### **CNN from Scratch**

#### Python

A simple implementation of a convolutional neural network using Python and NumPy, trained on the NumtaDB dataset to recognize Bengali digits.

Chaldaal (Web App)
django/python, oracle/sql, HTML/CSS, JS Created an online grocery shop similar to chaldal.com

# **Smart Construction Work System (Web App)** *Django, SQLite, HTML/CSS, JS*

Developed a citywide smart construction management system